Every city has a breaking point.
1992 is a crime, thriller, action film directed by Ariel Vromen.
In 1992, Mercer is desperately trying to rebuild his life and his relationship with his son
amidst the turbulent Los Angeles uprising following the Rodney King verdict.
Across town, another father and son put their own strained relationship to the test as they plot a dangerous heist
to steal catalytic converters, which contain valuable platinum from the factory where Mercer works.
As tensions rise and chaos erupts, both families reach their
boiling points when their worlds collide.
Mercer, played by Tyrese Gibson.
Riggin Bigby, played by Scott Eastwood.
Lowell, played by Ray Liotta.
Dennis, played by Dylan Arnold.
Titus, played by Oleg Taktarov.
Copeland, played by Clé Bennett.
1992 is a 2024 American crime heist thriller film directed by Ariel Vromen
and written by Sascha Penn and Vromen from a story by Penn.
The film stars Tyrese Gibson, Scott Eastwood, and Ray Liotta.
Producer Dot da Genius makes a cameo appearance in the film as his film debut.
The working title of the film, April 29, 1992, refers to the first night of the 1992 Los Angeles
riots, which is when and where the film is set; the title was later simplified to 1992.
The film was released in the United States on August 30, 2024.
It received mixed reviews from critics and grossed $2.9 million worldwide.
The film explores themes of looting, race politics, street
riots, based on true story, racial tension.
The tone is intense.